<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fab City Blog</title>
    <description>Fab City Blog</description>
    <link>http://fabcity.github.io/blog/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://fabcity.github.io/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2016 18:00:22 +0200</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2016 18:00:22 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>The History of Architecture</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The video was made for the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.construmat.com/&quot;&gt;Costrumat&lt;/a&gt; 2015 in Barcelona, and illustrates how our way to shape habitat and build cities is connected to the technology development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/133676785&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://fabcity.github.io/blog/2016/04/12/the-history-of-architecture-video.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fabcity.github.io/blog/2016/04/12/the-history-of-architecture-video.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>FAB City Campus in Amsterdam</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/img/FABCityAMS.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;alt&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A ‘FabCity Campus’ has been set up as part of &lt;a href=&quot;http://europebypeople.nl/&quot;&gt;Europe by People&lt;/a&gt;, the Amsterdam EU2016 Arts &amp;amp; Design programme and it is inspired by the ‘Fab City’ project that started in Barcelona two years ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following the &lt;a href=&quot;http://fab.city&quot;&gt;FAB City&lt;/a&gt; project, in early April 2016 a temporary, a freely accessible Fab City Campus has been built at the head of Amsterdam’s Java Island in the city’s Eastern Harbour District. Conceived as a green, self-sustaining city, the FabCity Campus will comprise some 50 innovative pavilions, installations and prototypes. More than 400 young students, professionals, artists and creatives will develop the site into a sustainable urban area, where they will work, create, explore and present their solutions to current urban issues. The participants are from various educational backgrounds, including art academies, (technology) universities and vocational colleges. Amsterdam is one of the next candidate cities which will join the FAB City initiative in the following years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nowadays cities are where most of the planet’s population live, they offer the best opportunity to effect practical change at scale in a context to which people can relate. Cities are at the heart of addressing the social and environmental challenges of the 21st century.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FAB City project comprises an international think tank of civic leaders, fab lab champions, makers, urbanists and innovators working on changing paradigm of the current industrial economy where the city operates on a linear model of importing products and producing waste. The &lt;a href=&quot;http://europebypeople.nl/programme/fabcity-summit-2&quot;&gt;Fab City Expert Meeting&lt;/a&gt; is gathering world leaders on digital fabrication, innovation and urban design in order to look on future models of operations and research for the Fab City project. It will be organised in participatory sessions in which the best skills and knowledge from participants will be oriented towards a common direction of efforts in order to transform the way we work, live and play in cities. We aim to end up with a road map in order to look for funding and organisation opportunities for the future of Fab Cities.
The Expert Meeting is accessible only by invite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the evening of April 20th a &lt;a href=&quot;http://europebypeople.nl/programme/fabcity-summit&quot;&gt;public dialogue&lt;/a&gt; follows the Expert Meeting of the International Fab City network. Many of these participants will also join the discussion: &lt;em&gt;how can we make a Fab City?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-the-fab-city-campus&quot;&gt;About the FAB City Campus&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/img/fabcity-campus.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;alt&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FAB City Campus will take place from 11 April up and until 26 June. It will be inhabited by students, scientists and (social) entrepreneurs, and will also function as a big maker space; a place to collectively experiment, prototype and test new ways of creating an improved future urban environment. Fab City continues from April until the end of June and will consist of several pavilions showing different innovative ideas for the connected, self-sufficient and circular city, among which the cardboard &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fictionfactory.nl/home.php?p=whouse&quot;&gt;Wikkelhouse by Fiction Factory&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://citiesintransition.eu/publicatie/bam-3d-concrete-printer-at-fabcity-campus&quot;&gt;BAM 3D concrete printer&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information about the event and the complete list of speakers, please visit http://europebypeople.nl/fabcity-2/&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://fabcity.github.io/blog/2016/04/06/fab-city-amsterdam.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fabcity.github.io/blog/2016/04/06/fab-city-amsterdam.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to FAB City</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://fab.city&quot;&gt;FAB City&lt;/a&gt; is an international initiative which emerged from the global &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fabfoundation.org/fab-labs/&quot;&gt;Fab Lab (Fabrication Laboratory) Network&lt;/a&gt; in order to develop locally productive and globally connected self-sufficient cities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a practical approach to systemically address a range of social and environmental challenges within our cities by empowering citizens. We work on a new urban model of building and shaping cities that shifts how they source and use materials, from &lt;cite&gt;‘Products In Trash Out’ (PITO)&lt;/cite&gt; to &lt;cite&gt;‘Data In Data Out’ (DIDO)&lt;/cite&gt;. This means that more production occurs inside the city, along with recycling materials and meeting local needs through local inventiveness. A city’s imports and exports would mostly be found in the form of data (information, knowledge, design, code).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-does-it-mean-to-be-a-fab-city&quot;&gt;What does it mean to be a FAB City?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To become a FAB City requires having a more precise knowledge of the way that cities work. The evolution of the project will make it possible to create better systems of capturing and analysing data, developing knowledge about a city, and it will also the implementation of an evaluation system and meticulous monitoring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a great economic opportunity for participating cities. It will create new types of jobs and professions related to the knowledge economy and the development and implementation of new approaches and technological solutions, including:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Manufacturing locally, and creating global impact: A global network of cities that share knowledge and best practices on urban solutions emerging from citizens, companies, educational institutions, and governments. Local networks of Fab Labs and production centers connected to the larger global network of supply chains, sharing knowledge, best practices and projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Distributed energy production: With the advent of domestic batteries and efficiency improvements in solar and other means of clean power generation, energy distribution itself will face enormous changes. Distributed grids will change the role of households and businesses in power, water and resources distribution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Cryptocurrency for a new economy: Cities creating their own trade markets connected to a global economy, using a multi-currency and value system based on the blockchain and similar technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Food production and urban permaculture: Urban farming will scale up from experimental practice to large scale infrastructure. Local production of foods at domestic, neighbourhood and city scales, will create a closed loop system for food production and harvesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Educating for the future: incorporate a stronger emphasis on  learning-by-doing in education systems and curricula, and  engage all levels of education in finding solutions for local needs, through digital fabrication technologies, and  sharing them with global networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Building the future circular [spiral] economy: Reduce the amount of imported goods, food and resources like water or energy. Increase the use of recycled raw materials for the production of objects in cities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Collaboration between governments and the civil society: local government and civic organizations, start-ups, universities, and other organizations must work together in order to make a cultural shift that promotes the empowerment of the cities and their citizens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-does-a-fab-city-work&quot;&gt;How does a FAB City work?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the initiatives mentioned will be supported by technologies such as digital manufacturing, energy rehabilitation of buildings and neighbourhoods, smart energy networks, electrical mobility, urban permaculture, intelligent infrastructure, and related policy and regulatory approaches, among other solutions to be shared globally between cities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Fab City project operates within the Fab Lab network, using it as a global infrastructure and knowledge source for the transformation of cities. We propose a new approach to urban regeneration by starting from the innovative capacity of citizens.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://fabcity.github.io/blog/2016/03/11/welcome-to-fab-city.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fabcity.github.io/blog/2016/03/11/welcome-to-fab-city.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
